It wasn't until I was sitting in the airport, in the plane, that my nephew called and said,
Aunt Steph, it was a white supremacist. He filmed the entire thing on live stream.
I groaned and roared and screamed so loudly that the plane was delayed and taking off.
I roared in pain for my sister, my beautiful sister, pharmacist, who was serving in the east side.
I never knew if I would see her again. I roared also in pain.
For my brothers and sisters, who do not look like me, or like the defendant.
I roared in pain because he bought into the lies of this country,
that somehow, because of the amount of the chemical in our skin, we are superior.
We were not even the first ones here, in the U.S.
Okay?
Our black and brown brothers and sisters endured centuries, not years, centuries of oppression
as they built our buildings and produced our crops, by which the foundation of this country was built on.
They continue to endure oppression.
Even the Harvard lawyer is mistaken continually in the courtroom for the defendant and not the lawyer.
They continue to endure microaggressions.
They continue to have their families gunned down simply because of the color of their skin.
You heard some of the family members today reading from the Bible, offering forgiveness, offering peace,
showing the beauty of their hearts.
Yes, you also saw the fury.
And for those who serve, who have to ask people to sit,
I ask you to do it with an empathy in your heart and an understanding
that for hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of years,
we have been looking at our brown brothers and sisters as if they were less than.
They are not less than.
They deserve our respect.
They deserve our radical empathy.
They deserve for us to get educated on what we can do to treat them with the respect that they deserve.